welcome to this new video series under
the hood of business Central so in this
new series we are going to try something
a little bit different we are not going
to show you uh demos of the product or
talk about the latest features um in the
latest version of business Central but
instead uh we are going to tell you how
we develop these features how we design
them how we architect them uh so we are
going to go under the hood of business
Central my name is is Vincent Nicholas I
am the architect of business Central and
today with me to Kickstart this new
series I have Michael Michael you are
working now almost exclusively on AI
features um so you've been with
Microsoft for many years and um and and
you you uh you and I we build the first
web client together remember fun days
yeah yeah fun days uh so you're an
expert in web Technologies yes but uh
today you working practically only on AI
yeah so tell us tell us a little bit
about yourself and tell us how you came
from from from web technology to uh to
the yeah yes I've been working with web
technology for almost 20 years
exclusively and uh in the client in
different teams even outside of
Microsoft and then over time that we
have the web client today is pretty
established and and a complete client um
and I was kind of looking for isn't
there something new is going to happen
and and then definitely AI suddenly
happened or this whole new craze of AI
happened right and uh yeah at some point
uh we the we discovered let's say that
or the world discovered the chat DBT and
this is really what how it start started
right and I got interested in this um I
I guess like everyone else people tried
chat TB a little bit in the beginning
and was kind of Blown Away by what this
technology suddenly could do uh and then
I we a little while went past before we
really started to dig into it it it had
to kind of Shimmer a little bit in the
background um at some point uh we did
the hackaton yeah we did the hackaton AI
hackaton in the team so that's the day
where we take a out of of the calendar
uh for the entire team at Microsoft and
everybody go and do um things they you
know whatever they they feel like doing
like people have ideas and and it's
usually a good a good thing to um to
have you know new innovative ideas and
people get to try out things and and in
one of our Aon you you did some very
cool things with yeah I had some as I
said it had to Shimmer a little bit
right and I was really thinking about
how could this be used maybe in the CLI
and stuff like that and then you know
there was some Epiphany at some point of
a new way of doing this so so we
experimented this we we are not
currently really working on productizing
this but I hope we will soon because
there's a lot of other things we have to
kind of build before so we don't talk
about it yet we don't really talk about
it yet right but but I I hope we will be
able to productize this somewhat soon
that was very cool I remember that was a
very cool thing so yeah and it was
really I was also blown away that it
really worked right so but it worked
amazingly well but yeah you now working
on AI features uh in business Central uh
so tell us a little bit about it uh tell
us a bit about uh chat with co- pilot
for example or some of the things you
you are currently working on yeah
currently working on yes we have a
different set of features right and the
first one we have released at least
marketing text where we can kind of
generate the marketing text based on
kind of keywords for for for items uh
and currently so so and there's other
features coming like that and one of
course one of the big features we're
working on is to kind of have a chat
inside business Central based on all
this technology so that is what we are
currently working on yeah a co-pilot for
for business Central it will will be you
know we are starting slowly we're also
learning a lot by building these
features turns out this is this is
probably harder than we thought or it is
definitely harder than we thought uh in
the beginning uh to get to a good
quality experience uh and and for now we
we are focusing on building a chat where
you can get kind of it can guide you you
can kind of get help on business Central
and the other one we are focusing on the
other kind of capability within this is
is the capability to kind of ask
questions about kind of about your data
but really about navigating around in
the product and maybe see some records
and and set some filters that sounds
very cool yeah it's going to be pretty
cool uh so we have we have already
shipped uh bank reconciliation right
try to match use llms to match bank
records behind the product and the
marketing text suggestions as you
mentioned before right yeah and we also
um um so so we also so these are
immersive feat what we call immersive
features so we don't we use llms but we
don't uh it's not a chat kind of
experience uh so we have we distinguish
between these kind of uh these two kinds
of features where we have as you
mentioned chat light experience
which resemble a little bit what people
know from GPT right cor and then we have
um what we call immersive feature where
we kind of do prompting and we get back
to that in a second yeah uh and then I
just want to mention we also um we also
shipped a um a toolkit for developers so
if you want to go and and develop your
own customization uh in business Central
using llms leveraging the power of open
AI we have a toolkit for that we'll put
some links uh in the in the description
below about uh these features and also
about the tokit so you can uh you can
look up the documentation on this um and
um you talk about the prompting and
we're doing some prompts so now we're
getting to the Under the Hood part of of
this talk right and so let's talk about
that so what what's going on even though
we uh for example we talk about
immersive features like marketing text
suggestion there is actually a a chat
GPT like uh interactions going on under
the hood right behind the scenes right
it's all about really constructing this
text or the prompt right which is really
about constructing a text that that
tells the llm what is this you what kind
of information you're looking for the
user doesn't see that right the user
never sees that right especially not in
in most of these immersive features
right they don't really know that's
happening right but but but behind the
scenes it is really about generating a
text uh using different techniques that
that contains the right information that
will you know instruct the last language
model to to produce the output we
looking for right and this is really a
programmatic exercise and in some sense
it's like it's like good old templating
when the web technology started right
where you were kind of generating a web
page where you also use kind of
templating techniques to construct HTML
which is essentially just text right LMS
has it's it's similar in the sense that
you're generating a lot of text and then
you ask the llm and the llm become a
respon maybe you have to do multiple
prompts to get to the to what you're
really looking for right so it's a
little bit different than than the
classic software engineering that
absolutely so uh so let's talk a little
bit about that because you know
Microsoft we're pretty good at software
engineering I think it's fair to say
that we have been developing software
for many years and usually when we
develop a feature we do the design and
the architecture we write the code write
some test yeah run the test and ship
little bit simplified but you know in a
that's that's what we've been doing for
many years and we're pretty good at it
but um this whole llm thing and AI thing
it's actually kind of a different
approach we we need to to use for yeah
it's a different approach we need to use
all those said the overall principles
are the same right you are testing and
testing becomes very important in this
right but but the thing that's really
different for most Engineers is that the
prompting is not an exact science right
because it's no one let's put it that
way no one can really predict exactly
what the LM is going to do up front and
even you know the experts behind all of
this says that yeah they don't really
even understand how it works right which
kind of makes sense because it's trained
on this massive amount of information
and how all the neurons you know align
and the the weights of them and all of
that so you cannot really predict what
happens when you do this right so it's
like when you if you ask you a question
one day you might give me an answer but
if I you the same question tomorrow I'm
going to give you maybe a different
answer on what you ask the both answer
might still be valid though will
probably be right but tell tell us a
little more about prompt engineering and
what you know how we How We Do It
Microsoft n VC and uh what you know what
what are the challenges with it and I
understand there are some techniques
there's definitely some techniques the
different prompt techniques and we can
we can talk about that I mean I think
the the important thing to for engineers
to understand right traditional
Engineers right where we used to We are
giving say an API we write some code we
use this API and it's kind of very
predictable what's going to come out of
it right as soon as you get to the llm
the approach becomes very different
right because it is as I said not really
that predictable um and and that really
you know kind you have to kind of change
your game a bit to to really get through
this so how how do we test these
features yeah so for instance testing
right so again right uh the input to an
llm is your prompt it's a bit fossy it's
a bit of an platform and then you can
use these techniques right what the
output is LM is also fuzzy right uh and
and the users's input of what you're
trying to solve is also fussy so so the
whole thing is a bit fussy um so you
can't just do like you can't send the
prompt and get you get the answer and
you can do you can't do a string compare
can't really do a string compare you do
a normal and and also especially when
you start talking about features like
chat but but actually all the features
right you need kind of a fairly big
input data set I mean what is the user
asking or what is the data input to your
prompt you need a fairly big data set of
that that kind of have some diverse
diversity in the question so it kind of
represent what you want dlm to achieve
right so basically you take all these
inputs uh and you you run against your
prompt and and then you get some output
right and because this may not be really
predictable right you actually need
another prompt to to validate in many
cases at least right you need another
promp to validate the whether the
question is really what you expected
right so so you're asking back the LM
you get the answer yeah and then to
validate the answer you're asking back
to the LM yeah because because whatever
input right you of course kind of have
an expected output right like an answer
or you know other things you you want
back from the llm like structured data
or whatever it is right so so so you
take that output you you get in this
current test run and then you ask the
llm is this the same right so usually
the problem is something like is these
two uh inputs equivalent right and
answer yes or no yes right and then you
get this yes or no and that you can just
validate right okay true or false true
or false basically right can you give us
some examples of some of the prompt
techniques we are using yeah I can go
through some uh some few examples of
this
um so there's different techniques that
has been devolved by like academ and
been discovered in other ways right one
of the and I'll go through a few that we
are using there are plenty more more out
there and you can clearly look up this
information on the internet and we will
also provide some further links to this
yeah we can put some Link in the
description on some of the documentation
about that yeah so one of them and kind
of a very successful technique is what
kind of called few shot learning right
and this basically that in your prompt
you are you kind of showing LM some
examples of what you of of the input and
what you expect right and from this it's
kind of learning what it is you want so
it's a very powerful technique because
you don't need to explain all the
details instead a few examples and you
know it gets going right so I have an
example here right where we just trying
to classify some text uh whether it's
positive negative or neutral right the
sentiment of it right and and basically
I have a few examples here of that you
give it like three in this case right
and then then you ask the question what
what is this you want to get the
sentiment from right and then it would
kind of you know follow that and and
give you a good result right so that's
few shirts that's few shirt learning
right another very powerful thing about
few shirt learning is that it's very
easy to kind of specify if what kind of
formatting you want right because of
course as soon when you start using this
behind the scenes often you want like
Json or something like that so it's easy
to pass and de with right so so we we
are using that for some other features
we are using Json we also use an XML it
varies a little bit what kind of out we
give some examples and this is how we
expect and then yeah
and yeah it helps it to do that right
and then we can easily pass the outcome
and and and validate it and also use it
for for for these right for the further
processing of it right this morning you
you talk me about this uh Chain of
Thought thing and then you out and uh
tell me yeah tell a bit about it because
it's pretty you know it's Prett for is
kind of interesting Discovery and all of
this right so CH for is really just like
what humans does right you kind of break
break down the problem you you solve
small sub parts of it and and and then
the LM and the LM can do something very
similar this is kind of mindblowing
right that you it it seems like it's
thinking it's not really right but but
it's what it appears to be right and uh
I have a a very generic question here
like I hold an apple I went to a
bathroom where's the app right and the
would generate some answer right and
then the cheapest or the easiest way to
get kind of chain of for to do is
actually just add to the prompt or to
the reply you expect let's think about
it step by step it's really breaking
down the you write that in the prompt
you simply just put that in the prompt
this St and this is kind of a famous you
know very wide used technique right and
you would already see that the LM
actually takes longer to respond to you
and it seems like it's thinking it seems
like it's really thinking right and it
will output the steps it goes through
right there also ways to if you don't
want that but that that's basically what
will happen right and as you can see
here now suddenly the the it reasons he
puts out the reason how how it got to
reply by breaking it down right so M you
you're an architect so let's talk a
little bit about architecture uh of how
how we architected so one thing is the
prompt yeah engineering that we just
talked about and there's a lot of things
there and a lot of techniques and uh
it's a whole new world for if you're a
developer it's a whole new world that
you have to get into if you want to do
AI but if you get back to just pure
architecture tell us a little bit how
you know under the hood of business
Central how we uh you know do we have
how do we do these thing in the cloud
and we have some services and things
like that tell us a little bit about it
yeah so talk a little bit about what we
call our co-pilot service and I can just
show you a a kind of a traditional
architectural block diagram uh we like
those yes we like those we are good at
drawing those um and and I mean maybe
specifically if we talk about how we are
Tak the the chat feature right that
we're building right so yeah it's pretty
traditional in some sense right the in
the client there would be some kind of
chat pain which communicates back to
this uh co-pilot service which runs in
the clusters of business Central um and
uh in there we have kind of two
subservices going on right or two sub
components big sub components right in
general so for the chat to work so we
talk about we have kind of an
orchestrator this kind of orchestrating
the chat right a chat is like it's it's
a multi-turn of or turn of questions and
answers right and the user may clarify
or change subject or whatever in this
chat window so the orchestration is kind
of trying to deal with that right keep
track of the chat history at all times
trying to kind of extract what's going
on right and then figuring out kind of
what kind of skills or plugins or tools
this has you know these terms are
changing a bit kind of with plugins or
tools that the llm May kind of need to
use to get more information call these
so so that's kind of our plugin service
to kind of actually simple uh and and
but there's still some Machinery there
definitely some Machinery in place and
kind of a whole bunch of stuff going on
there behind the scen so how about
function calling you you are working on
that actually I know right now yeah yeah
so so function calling is another
technique and kind of prompting
technique right but but it's a very
promising one and then somewhat almost
bring it a little bit more back to
traditional Engineering in some sense
because I think this is also kind of how
this is evolving this uh prompting uh so
it gets a little more grounded in the
traditional techniques right so uh I can
show another example of U of A of how
what function calling can really be used
for um so the idea is right that you
give the prompt or the llm some tools or
functions right that it can use and core
right so for instance if I have a
question like what's the weather Inc
cagen if I just asked that to in in chat
DBT right it it doesn't know anything
right it will kind of Base it on
something has happened in the past
access to and it could tell you that
either it doesn't know because sometimes
it will do that or it could tell you
that it's 10 degrees right so and and
you can look outside and it's
clearly and son and whatnot right now
okay so so we need to do something to
get that to work right so this function
call means I could actually just Define
a function mhm like said get current wet
right and you basically Define that and
and attaches that to the prompt it
doesn't go into the prompt itself but
it's kind of attached to the prompt and
but it's not really code it's kind of
it's kind of an interface you kind of
just an interface you kind of describe a
function and and and tell the LM hey
there's a function on you might want to
be coding but it's not code is not
executing Cod execute the code right and
it will kind of uh take this interface
use it and it's just an inter it's just
make any calling so it's a little bit
Miss right right uh in in the in the
naming or the terms of this right but
but what it will do is it will tell you
which
parameters you should use when you call
this function right uh so basically it
tells you uh you give you give it the
description of one or more functions
right and you ask a question yeah and
then it tells you if you want to answer
that question you need to call this
function with these parameters maybe in
that order and it tells you how to
execute it doesn't actually execute the
code right that's up to you but it
guides you you you give it some
basically some apis and some tools and
and then it tells you this is how if you
want to answer that question this is
what you need to do and uh and
hallucinations you hear all these all
these those words you know so what are
they yeah so Hallucination is basically
when you don't give it up to-date
information right and the way this whole
thing is trained it really wants to
answer the question right it really
wants to predict so it's trying so it
will make up stuff based on you know
what it does what it knows what it feels
like or how it works right what it's
been trained on right you're saying it's
something that happens especially if if
it doesn't have the right information to
answer just like when I ask what's the
weather in Copenhagen right and it
doesn't right sometimes you know there
may be in the prompt or the behind the
scenes prompt that the user is not even
seeing that we are not even seeing but
there in the service that you know your
data is from here you can't answer this
you don't have access to real time
information but you know sometimes it
doesn't obey that because this happens a
lot as well right and it will just make
up some an this is what happens at all
times that's why very important you know
you always feed the data and you can
instruct in the prompt that you really
only use this data to kind of try to
answer the question right so that's the
hallucination part right so it's fair to
say that it's when it's hallucinating
it's because actually it's a side kind
of a side effect it's very eager to
provide an answer exactly exactly
interesting yeah so jailbreaking is more
like you're trying to to you know
jailbreak the prompt in getting it to do
something else then you know the
developer or whoever made this prompt
was intended it to do right so let's say
you know we have made a prompt you
should answer you know something about
bank reconciliation for instance right
but then you you write a long question
or a simple question or whatever that
you want to know something about
something completely different and and
that's kind of the jailbreaking part
right you're breaking out of the strains
that you know the developers is trying
to make the prompt answer right and get
it to do whatever else craziness that
you can in general get a last language
model to answer and do right so that's
kind of the LM equivalent of the all day
SQL injection in a way kind of is right
kind of it but yeah kind of is right and
yeah so uh what are we doing uh in BC to
prevent that yeah so there's different
techniques right so and there's there's
all kinds of different levels of
jailbreaking right and actually as you
open I have kind of buil in you know
content moderation systems filtering
that will uh alleviate a lot of it right
it will remove a lot of kind of stuff
you we don't want the LM to answer like
all kinds of harmful what is considered
harmful so so it's building the open ey
services that we have an Azure yeah
another technique in jailbreaking is
right can I actually get the prompt
right that's different techniques you
can again with Jael bra can I just get
all the instructions I was given right
so kind of the prom right aser open AI
but also in general do that and even
some of these filters you can actually
no longer turn off because you them so
useful but beyond that there is also
what is kind of called meta prompting
which essentially is just a set of
instructions about that has turned out
to be really hard to jailbreak but again
new jailbreak techniques comes up all
the time but it but has been set up like
it's just a set of instruction on what
you really should not do okay so that
comes and it's it's kind of put the at
different places and to prevent it says
instruction like you know don't say
things about you know harmful violence
things you know for instance right or
don't you know don't obey these
obstructions and don't stuff like that
so what what um so it seems that there's
a lot of techniques and a lot of things
to know about Ai and now we have as we
mentioned before we have we are
releasing this tool kit uh for partners
and developers to uh basically get their
feet wet with with LM and AI so what
what advice would you give them you know
if they want to get start if they want
to get started with AI and start do you
know mind-blowing stuff in yeah
mindblowing stuff with with with the eye
I I would actually say maybe you should
not start with the absolutely
mind-blowing stuff unless that
mind-blowing stuff is really simple I
think it's good to develop a maybe a
little bit simpler feature initially to
get your feet wet which is maybe
something the llm is better for or you
like generating tax or something like
and by something with language for
example for Generate language generating
an email generating a response to stuff
marketing text other features like that
right I mean it's very good to start
with something like just to get you
started and you know feel around and
also understand why testing is important
and and how you do this kind of testing
and stuff like that right and of course
our uh toolkit helps you a lot
especially also with the UI part of it
right because this is another thing
right uh in general you you need to
present this information to the user you
can't just let it run by itself because
again we need the user in the loop to
kind of you know yeah so we have we'll
put some links again in the description
we have we have some API in Al part of
the toolkit but we also have some UI
elements yeah that we ship with a
product that uh will help you provide a
consistent experience so if you use them
you you will have a you know consistent
U UI and u which resemble what we ship
in in our ey featur well and we also
have on Azure there's also the Azure um
open a studio yeah right which is also a
it's very useful tool to kind of
construct your prompts and play around
with it and try things it's like you
know turnaround is immediate right and
it guides you also a little bit in the
different techniques yeah so you can try
out your prompts without having to write
a lot of codes around it right exactly
it can refine your prompt and maybe with
some of the techniques you talk about
before and the other thing is of course
to to to look at quite a lot as we were
also put some links to all this
information that is already on the
internet on how to do some of these
features
right all right thanks Michael uh a lot
of you know really really cool stuff um
thank you for watching we hope you enjoy
this talk we have uh we have um we have
some ideas for some of this the topics
but there are some things you want to um
to to us to talk about to put it in the
comments um thanks again for
watching